<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhigang Lu</title>
    <link>https://zglu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zhigang Lu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://zglu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://zglu.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zglu.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>h-index: 11 Links to my Google Scholar and ResearchGate

2022  Buddenborg SK, Tracey A, Berger DJ, Lu Z, Doyle SR, Fu B, et al. (2021). Assembled chromosomes of the blood fluke Schistosoma mansoni provide insight into the evolution of its ZW sex-determination system. BMC Biol. (in revision) /bioRxiv. 2021.08.13.456314  2021  Rawlinson KA, Reid AJ, Lu Z, Driguez P, Wawer A, Coghlan A, et al. (2021). Daily rhythms in gene expression of the human parasite Schistosoma mansoni.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SingleCellAtlas</title>
      <link>https://zglu.github.io/singlecellatlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zglu.github.io/singlecellatlas/</guid>
      <description>Single Cell Atlas Collection of single cell atlas papers and data portals.
Mapping cell types across human tissues  Single-nucleus cross-tissue molecular reference maps toward understanding disease gene function [https://singlecell.broadinstitute.org/single_cell/study/SCP1479] The Tabula Sapiens: A multiple-organ, single-cell transcriptomic atlas of humans [https://tabula-sapiens-portal.ds.czbiohub.org/] Cross-tissue immune cell analysis reveals tissue-specific features in humans [https://www.celltypist.org/] Mapping the developing human immune system across organs Brain Cell Network [https://biccn.org/] Cells of the adult human heart [http://www.heartcellatlas.org/]   Spatio-temporal development of model organisms  Spatiotemporal transcriptomic atlas of mouse organogenesis using DNA nanoball-patterned arrays [https://db.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SingleCellTools</title>
      <link>https://zglu.github.io/singlecelltools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zglu.github.io/singlecelltools/</guid>
      <description>Selected tools for single-cell and spatial transcriptomics.
scRNA-seq  Zero-preserving imputation: ALRA   spatial transcriptomics  segmentation-free inference of cell types: SSAM &amp;amp; SSAM lite   Integration of single cell data Benchmarking analysis  Benchmarking spatial and single-cell transcriptomics integration methods for transcript distribution prediction and cell type deconvolution  Selected tools  PASTE: Alignment and integration of spatial transcriptomics data from multiple adjacent tissue slices (Python) GLUE: Multi-omics single-cell data integration and regulatory inference with graph-linked embedding (Python/R) CellTrek: Spatial charting of single-cell transcriptomes in tissues (R) Tangram: aligns sc/snRNA-seq data to patial data (Python) SPOTlight: integration of Spatial Transcriptomics with scRNA-seq data to infer the location of cell types and states (R) cell2location: Cell2location maps fine-grained cell types in spatial transcriptomics (Python)   Single cell data interactive visualisation  Comparison of visualization tools for single-cell RNAseq data Seurat interactive plotting (HoverLocator())   Other tools  sceasy: easy conversion of different single-cell data formats (R)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
