<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhigang Lu</title>
    <link>https://zglu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zhigang Lu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://zglu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CellBrowser</title>
      <link>https://zglu.github.io/cellbrowser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zglu.github.io/cellbrowser/</guid>
      <description>Explore single-cell and spatial data using UCSC Cell Browser. Here are some instances I built:
 Visium_Mouse_Brain_Sagittal_Posterior_Section_2   Stereo-seq_Mouse_E9.5_Bin100   CellBrowser 100-genes demo scRNA-seq  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://zglu.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zglu.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>h-index: 12 Links to my Google Scholar and ResearchGate

2022  Buddenborg SK, Tracey A, Berger DJ, Lu Z, Doyle SR, Fu B, et al. (2021). Assembled chromosomes of the blood fluke Schistosoma mansoni provide insight into the evolution of its ZW sex-determination system. BMC Biol. (in revision) /bioRxiv. 2021.08.13.456314  2021  Rawlinson KA, Reid AJ, Lu Z, Driguez P, Wawer A, Coghlan A, et al. (2021). Daily rhythms in gene expression of the human parasite Schistosoma mansoni.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SingleCellAtlas</title>
      <link>https://zglu.github.io/singlecellatlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zglu.github.io/singlecellatlas/</guid>
      <description>Single Cell Atlas Collection of single cell atlas papers and data portals.
Mapping cell types across human tissues  Single-nucleus cross-tissue molecular reference maps toward understanding disease gene function [https://singlecell.broadinstitute.org/single_cell/study/SCP1479] The Tabula Sapiens: A multiple-organ, single-cell transcriptomic atlas of humans [https://tabula-sapiens-portal.ds.czbiohub.org/] Cross-tissue immune cell analysis reveals tissue-specific features in humans [https://www.celltypist.org/] Mapping the developing human immune system across organs Brain Cell Network [https://biccn.org/] Cells of the adult human heart [http://www.heartcellatlas.org/]   Spatio-temporal development of model organisms  Spatial Transcript Omics DataBase (STOmics DB) Spatiotemporal transcriptomic atlas of mouse organogenesis using DNA nanoball-patterned arrays [https://db.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SingleCellTools</title>
      <link>https://zglu.github.io/singlecelltools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zglu.github.io/singlecelltools/</guid>
      <description>Selected tools for single-cell and spatial transcriptomics.
scRNA-seq  ALRA: Zero-preserving imputation HotSpot: identifies informative gene modules (pip install hotspotsc==0.9.1) SCENIC/pySCENIC: Single-cell regulatory network and clustering PROGENy &amp;amp; decoupleR: inference of pathway activities (human &amp;amp; mouse) MetaNeighbor: characterizing the replicability of cell types across datasets (R) SAMap: mapping cell atlas manifolds across species (py) MAGIC: imputing missing values and restoring the structure of single-cell data (R &amp;amp; py)   spatial transcriptomics  Giotto: toolbox for integrative analysis of spatial data (datasets) (GittoSuite) SpatialDE: identification of spatially variable genes (py) Spark: Statistical analysis of spatial expression patterns BayesSpace: Clustering and Resolution Enhancement of Spatial Transcriptomes SpaGCN: spatial domains and SVGs by graph convolutional network stLearn: downstream analysis toolkit for Spatial Transcriptomic data GCNG: GCN for inferring cell-cell interactions SpaOTsc: spatial optimal transport for SC data (py) DSSC: Deep Spatially constrained Single-cell Clustering (using spatial information and marker genes) RCTD: Robust Cell Type Decomposition C-SIDE: Cell type-specific inference of differential expression (spacexr = RCTD + C-SIDE; Vignettes)   Integration of single cell data Benchmarking analysis  Benchmarking spatial and single-cell transcriptomics integration methods for transcript distribution prediction and cell type deconvolution  Selected tools  PASTE: Alignment and integration of spatial transcriptomics data from multiple adjacent tissue slices (Python) GLUE: Multi-omics single-cell data integration and regulatory inference with graph-linked embedding (Python/R) CellTrek: Spatial charting of single-cell transcriptomes in tissues (R) Tangram: aligns sc/snRNA-seq data to spatial data (Python) SPOTlight: integration of Spatial Transcriptomics with scRNA-seq data to infer the location of cell types and states (R) Harmony: Fast, sensitive and accurate integration of single-cell data (R) cell2location: Cell2location maps fine-grained cell types in spatial transcriptomics (Python)   Single cell data interactive visualisation  Comparison of visualization tools for single-cell RNAseq data Seurat interactive plotting (HoverLocator()) Plotly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
